<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joel Becker</title>
    <link>https://joel-becker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Joel Becker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joel-becker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pointing to my aesthetic tastes</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/aesthetic-tastes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/aesthetic-tastes/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t have a good articulation of my current aesthetic tastes. (Because I am insufficiently articulate and/or they are incoherent.) But here are some pointers.
Good (I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to make this close-ish-to-orthogonal to my enjoyment of these things, but mostly failed):
Purple. Truth-seeking, the activity. Sports as religion. Musical theatre, Kendrick, JME, 00&amp;rsquo;s bangers, Jacob Collier, melody-free techno. The future belongs to the obsessed. Inter-generational living. Harshly subverting gendered expectations. Exaggeration for effect, gesticulation, moving around whilst in conversation, Camille Paglia&amp;rsquo;s speaking style.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fool people into thinking you&#39;re good at music</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/music-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/music-tricks/</guid>
      <description>Minimum Viable Piano Use only root notes, 1 octave apart, in the left hand. More feels too busy. Transition between chords using reasonable notes (again separated by an octave) in the left hand. Any note in the triad of the chord being transitioned to. Any note that is (a) inside the shortest distance between the root note being transitioned from and root note being transitioned to and (b) in the key of the song.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intuitions about singalongs</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/intuitions-singalongs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/intuitions-singalongs/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve led many a singalong. Some better, some worse. The good ones typically have a couple of things in common:
Multiple guitars. 3+ really enthusiastic singers. Enough participants. 5+ necessary, 10+ starting to get ideal, 100+ is unnecessary but magical. 50%+ of the group know all words in the choruses of 50%+ of songs played. Songs that few people know are quit very quickly. Participants are made to feel included (ideally central, but at least in-on-the-fun).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-constrained optimization</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/self-constrained-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/self-constrained-optimization/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a sense in which people who binge netflix are honestly expressing their preferences. They could go for a run, or meditate, or call a friend. If instead they choose netflix, perhaps we should think they prefer netflix by revealed preference.
[DIAGRAM OF NETFLIX VS NOT NETFLIX, WITH CONSTRAINTS]
Yet it&amp;rsquo;s hard to suppress the nagging sense that something is going wrong here. Perhaps the netflix-binger themself feels that their bingeing behavior is getting in the way of what they want to want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invisible differences in internal experience</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/invisible-differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/invisible-differences/</guid>
      <description>Maybe there are many axes of internal experience with significant variation; aphantasia/vividness of visual imagery is merely easiest to name.
Some candidates:
Vividness of imagination for senses other than sight &amp;ndash; smell, taste, touch. Stability/control of imagination. Seeing connections/structure vs. more descriptive picture &amp;ndash; paranoia/apophenia, literal-mindedness. Strength of associations &amp;ndash; bouba/kiki, synesthesia. Internal monologue vs&amp;hellip; mentalese? Intensity of sensory experience. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midwit Self-Experimentation</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/midwit-quantified-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/midwit-quantified-self/</guid>
      <description>Dumb On the left, we have the dumbest approach to self-experimentation: just try stuff.
From day 0 (today) until day N, try something. See how you feel. If you want to take a more explicit approach, take the difference between
Midwit Smart </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A frame for deciding to take ADHD meds</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/adhd-meds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/adhd-meds/</guid>
      <description>This is a frame that I casually share with friends, not medical advice. I&amp;rsquo;m not a doctor of any kind.
The frame shades negative because that&amp;rsquo;s what I think is more useful for friends to hear.
The frame ADHD meds give you another option for how to work, with some significant upsides and some significant downsides. It&amp;rsquo;s annoying but possible to transition between periods of using to not using, and it&amp;rsquo;s annoying but possible in a different way to be half-way between using and not using within same period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideal workout routine for someone with exactly my preferences and constraints</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/ideal-workout-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/ideal-workout-routine/</guid>
      <description>For why I like 1 set per workout so much, see this post; for why I like multiple types of workouts per day, see this post.
Day 1: Soccer Ideally ~90 minutes.
Day 2: Pull-Legs-Stretch 1x pull-up 1x chin-up 2x romanian deadlift (or squat), barbell 1x bent-over row, barbell 1x hack squat 1x hip thrust, machine 1x seated leg press 1x seated row, cable or plate-loaded 1x glute-ham raise 1x archer curl 1x seated leg curl 1x vertical traction 1x single-arm preacher curl, machine 1x leg extension 1x reverse fly, cable 5-15 mins stretching</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mash-ups</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/mashups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/mashups/</guid>
      <description>Mash-ups are one of my favorite things about sing-alongs. They can sound great, and often lead to comic surprise. Some of my favorites:
Song Approximate Chord Progression Fits Progression Relative Timing Wonderwall i - III - VII - IV Yes Normal Boulevard of Broken Dreams i - III - VII - IV Yes Normal Mad World i - III - VII - IV Yes Normal A Team i - III - VII - IV Yes Double-tempo (pre-chorus) Let It Go i - III - VII - IV Yes Normal (verses) Skinny Love i - III - VII - IV Yes Double-tempo Radioactive i - III - VII - IV Yes Normal Pumped Up Kicks i - III - VII - IV Yes Normal Just Dance i - III - VII - IV Yes Half-tempo Sweet Child O&amp;rsquo; Mine I - VII - IV - I Yes Normal (verses) Take Your Mama I - VII - IV - I Yes Normal Music In Me I - VII - IV - I Yes Normal Safety Dance I - VII - IV - I Almost Normal Champagne Supernova I - VII - IV - I Almost Normal Stand By Me I - vi - IV - V - I Yes Normal Beautiful Girls I - vi - IV - V - I Yes Normal Who Knew I - vi - IV - V - I Almost Normal I&amp;rsquo;ll Follow You Into The Dark I - vi - IV - V - I Almost Normal (verses) How To Save A Life I - vi - IV - V - I Almost Normal Riptide I - vi - IV - V - I Stretch Normal Blank Space I - vi - IV - V - I Almost Double-tempo Baby One More Time i - V - iii - IV - V Yes Normal Havana i - V - iii - IV - V Yes Normal Levitating i - V - iii - IV - V Almost Normal Alexander Hamilton i - V - iii - IV - V Almost Normal My Shot i - V - iii - IV - V Almost Normal Hotel California i - V - iii - IV - V Stretch Normal Lose Yourself i - V - iii - IV - V Stretch Normal Sweet Dreams Are Made Of This vi - IV - V/vi Yes Normal Everybody (Backstreet&amp;rsquo;s Back) vi - IV - V/vi Yes Normal Bet On It vi - IV - V/vi Yes Normal (verses) Survivor vi - IV - V/vi Almost Normal Save Tonight vi - IV - I - V Yes Double-tempo Thrift Shop vi - IV - I - V Yes Normal Sparks Fly vi - IV - I - V Yes Normal California Gurls vi - IV - I - V Yes Normal We Found Love vi - IV - I - V Yes Normal Just A Dream vi - IV - I - V Yes Double-tempo If I Die Young vi - IV - I - V Yes Normal Written In The Stars vi - IV - I - V Yes Double-tempo Burn vi - IV - I - V Yes Normal If I Were A Boy vi - IV - I - V Yes Normal I&amp;rsquo;m Not Afraid vi - IV - I - V Yes Double-tempo Magic vi - IV - I - V Yes Normal Stay With Me vi - IV - I - V Yes Normal Love The Way You Lie Part 2 vi - IV - I - V Yes Normal Wing$ vi - IV - I - V Almost Double-tempo </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 set per exercise</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/1-set-per-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/1-set-per-exercise/</guid>
      <description>I prefer for my weightlifting workouts to involve just 1 set per exercise.
There isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly conventional wisdom on this question, but it&amp;rsquo;s extremely common to stick with 3 or so sets per exercise. Defenders of the status quo, when pressed, say something like &amp;ldquo;3 sets helps you measure progression,&amp;rdquo; which is obviously nonsense (you could still maintain a consistent ordered list of exercises with 1 set per exercise).
What are the trade-offs?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions about AI</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/ai-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/ai-questions/</guid>
      <description>Are there distributed training schemes that don&amp;rsquo;t require syncing weights at end of each training step? (My understanding is that even &amp;lsquo;async&amp;rsquo; approaches require this.) Feels like you could apply old grad updates like momentum - but discounted in ~time rather than training steps. Why doesn&amp;rsquo;t initializing with existing model weights work in NLP?. Or, if it does, why isn&amp;rsquo;t it more common? What is the best practice for training smaller models in a language model family?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>80,000 Hours, Actually After Hours</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/80k-after-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/80k-after-hours/</guid>
      <description>We ended up discussing a lot of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve written about here: fellowship programs, the pull of America, my experience of aphantasia, and meta-preferences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SingalongTech</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/singalong-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/singalong-tech/</guid>
      <description>My friend Rob created this helpful app for proposing and voting on songs to sing along to. It came to mind a couple of months later, when I joined my first Manifold hackathon.
For background, I love incongruent mash-ups. These can be hard to find except through trial-and-error&amp;hellip; until LLMs.
Behold, my joint-winning hackathon project, the mash-up generator. (Apologies that the code is so untidy/bad and the project very unfinished. Please feel free to further develop this idea, then send me a link or PR!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategic</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/strategic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/strategic/</guid>
      <description>Humans are not automatically strategic, but here are some examples of times where they have been. (Some are cleaner than others.)
Sports and gambling My recommended workout split Statsbomb and set-pieces Cate Hall and physical reads Moneyball Pep Guardiola and the False 9 Muhammad Ali and the rope-a-dope Fosbury Flop The Three-Point Revolution Disruptive businesses Ikea and flat-pack furniture SpaceX Google and PageRank RenTec Academia Alice Evans ignoring (presumed) incentives in academic publishing Productivity FIRE movement Evidence-based study techniques Health Ignaz Semmelweis and handwashing Norman Borlaug and the Green Revolution War and politics Vote Leave Fabian strategy </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idiosyncrasies downstream of aphantasia</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/idiosyncrasies-downstream-aphantasia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/idiosyncrasies-downstream-aphantasia/</guid>
      <description>I have my idiosyncrasies. I have aphantasia. I wonder how many of my idiosyncrasies are downstream of aphantasia, given that the condition is not well understood.
Some candidates:
Weak recollection of auto-biographical details. Thinking much more clearly whilst walking than staying still. Difficulty understanding the plots of films and TV shows. I once watched Glengarry Glen Ross with a group of friends, got to the end of the film, and thought it would be funny to ask whether anyone understood the story, because I found the film impossible to follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An ontology of aphantasia</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/aphantasia-ontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/aphantasia-ontology/</guid>
      <description>I have aphantasia.
People usually respond to this fact with &amp;ldquo;how do you X&amp;rdquo; questions, which I feel helpless to answer, because there isn&amp;rsquo;t a well-developed language for these things.
How do I navigate in familiar spaces? I&amp;hellip; erm&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;feel&amp;rdquo; it&amp;hellip;? I can just sort of sense the spatial distance between things, without these things having visual representations. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit like if you were awake, closed your eyes and attempted to navigate a familiar space &amp;ndash; my guess is that people don&amp;rsquo;t imagine the table to be avoided 2 feet ahead of them, rather they have some spatial sense that doesn&amp;rsquo;t run through visual imagery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memeing myself/meta-preferences</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/memeing-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/memeing-myself/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I was feeling low after a professional set-back. I called up my friend Nuno.
&amp;ldquo;Do you want me to listen to your ramblings, or do you want to solve the problem?&amp;rdquo;
30 minutes later, we turned to solving the problem.
&amp;ldquo;You must stop self-pitying.&amp;rdquo;
After the call, I gave myself evidence that I was the kind of person who was on the path to achieving my goals. I started wearing nice clothes, made bold professional asks, and tried to be lively at social events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different hours have different value</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/hours-have-different-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/hours-have-different-value/</guid>
      <description>When you purchase an hour of time, it is not immediately obvious how much value you get, because (1) different hours have different value, and (2) it is not always clear which hour you are purchasing.
Different hours have different value Ways in which an hour can be more valuable to you include:
Time of day: morning, evening. Social context: with friends, with family, with strangers, alone. Location: at home, at work, at an art studio, on a beach, in a hospital.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignoring the future when valuing time</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/ignoring-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/ignoring-the-future/</guid>
      <description>Let’s suppose that all hours are equivalently valuable, and that you can easily earn more money by working more hours. There is still one more problem with valuing your time at your current average wage: not appropriately accounting for future benefits and costs.
Consider the following model of career progression:
In year \(0\), you are paid \($X\) (in nominal terms). In year \(1\), you are paid \($(X + W)\), or \($(X + W) \times R^{-1}\) in real terms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Mistakes When Valuing Time</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/mistakes-valuing-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/mistakes-valuing-time/</guid>
      <description>People who make somewhat explicit time-money trade-offs often use something like their average wage as a proxy for the &amp;ldquo;value of time&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; the price at which they are indifferent between spending money to save an hour and spending an hour to save money.
This is a reasonable start, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s mistaken, for at least 2 important reasons:
The value of a purchased hour depends on more than just wage level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The value of your time depends on more than just wages</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/more-than-wages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/more-than-wages/</guid>
      <description>I think that valuing time at your average wage is mistaken, for at least 3 reasons:
The value of a purchased hour depends on more than just wage level. [&amp;hellip;] In most instances, the more leisure time you have, the less you value an additional hour of it. [&amp;hellip;] Separate from how much work and leisure time you have when deciding to buy an hour, particular hours have characteristics &amp;ndash; energy level, time of day, location, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeing through clouds</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/seeing-through-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/seeing-through-clouds/</guid>
      <description>von Neumann would carry on a conversation with my 3-year-old son, and the two of them would talk as equals, and I sometimes wondered if he used the same principle when he talked to the rest of us.
Edward Teller
Seeing through clouds Masha Gessen once wrote a series of articles for Slate grappling with her BRCA mutation. In the third article, she meets with my old boss David Laibson, hoping that he might be able to help think through the problem of whether to get an Oophorectomy, a Mastectomy, both, or neither.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some types of friends I&#39;d like to make</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/types-of-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/types-of-friends/</guid>
      <description>Friend that complements existing hobbies. Karaoke-loving weightlifter. Soccer player who is into intense thinking retreats. Acoustic- or bass-guitar-playing event planner. Friend that expands my horizons. Poetry-writing mechanical engineer. Yoga-practicing interior designer. History-obsessed cook. Fancy-bar-tending cheese-taster. Friend that has extreme and almost-aspirational character traits. Earnestness and virtuosity, pointed in a very different direction to that which I am used to. Gregariousness, intentionally directed. Extremely into self-improvement, or extremely anti-self-improvement Unabashed boldness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The cost of an O-1 visa</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/cost-of-o1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/cost-of-o1/</guid>
      <description>Not legal advice.
I estimate that the O-1 visa process:
Cost me around $37k in resources and time working towards the visa (&amp;ldquo;accounting terms&amp;rdquo;), or $77k in resources, time working towards the visa, and time not working as a result of waiting for the visa (&amp;ldquo;economic terms&amp;rdquo;). Would have taken ~8 months excluding unrelated delays. Links to code for these estimates here and here.
The main cost estimate &amp;ndash; accounting cost &amp;ndash; consists of my time (~$12k), my PA&amp;rsquo;s time (~$7k), lawyer fees ($11k), administrative costs ($3k), and necessary organization expenses (~$4k).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masked Mixer</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/masked-mixer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/masked-mixer/</guid>
      <description>My friend Arden and I were curious about hosting a sensory deprivation (or heightening) event. We began brainstorming:
blindfolded hide-and-seek; but with a bell, or squeaky chickens (better if they can be quiet). in multiple bedrooms? with multiple seekers? mix ingredients together in one team, have second team blind taste it	play with general idea of one team makes a thing, other has to identify. maybe do it telephone style? sensory deprivation relay: diff team members have diff senses deprived muffled speed-dating karaoke but only the singer is muffled (maybe humiliation shared between 2 people, hard to stay in sync) blindfolded dancing blind jenga silent telephone of one kind of another event brainstorming cool event ideas Eventually, we settled on running a blindfolded dinner, giant jenga, and hide-and-seek event: a &amp;ldquo;masked mixer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some fun lessons I learned as a junior regrantor</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/regrantor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/regrantor/</guid>
      <description>Title in homage to Linch.
In the second half of 2022, I was a Manifund regrantor. I ended up funding:
Holly Elmore to “[organize] for a frontier AI moratorium.” ($2.5k.) Jordan Schneider/ChinaTalk to produce “deep coverage of China and AI.” ($17.55k.) Robert Long to conduct “empirical research into AI consciousness and moral patienthood.” ($7.2k.) Greg Sadler/GAP organizational expenses. ($10k.) Nuño Sempere to “make ALERT happen.” ($8k.) Zhonghao He to “[map] neuroscience and mechanistic interpretability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cafés I want to exist</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/cafes-to-exist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/cafes-to-exist/</guid>
      <description>Sauna and ice baths cafe. (Found something like this in Prague.) Dog cafe. (Boris and Horton, NYC.) Plant shop cafe. (REMI, NYC; kind of Frëims, CDMX.) Austrian delicatessen-cafe. (Wally&amp;rsquo;s Kaffeehaus, Cardiff.) Neapolitan cafe. (Gran Caffè Gambrinus, Naples.) Photography or art gallery cafe. (The Observatory Coffeeshop, London.) One day, I want to open several of these close to where I live.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diet is endogenous to exercise</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/exercise-vs-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/exercise-vs-diet/</guid>
      <description>There is a near-consensus that diet is more important than exercise, at least for aesthetics.
I think this idea suffers from a similar problem as that suffered by &amp;lsquo;calories in calories out&amp;rsquo;: although it might be true in some idealized sense, &amp;ldquo;calories out are endogenous to what is eaten&amp;rdquo;.
Here, diet-in-reality is largely determined by &amp;rsquo;the kind of person you believe yourself to be.&amp;rsquo; Exercising more makes it easier to see yourself as the kind of person who takes diet seriously, and therefore improves diet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect Day</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/perfect-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/perfect-day/</guid>
      <description>The 4th of the famous 36 questions for falling in love is: &amp;ldquo;What would constitute a &amp;lsquo;perfect&amp;rsquo; day for you?&amp;rdquo; On September 10th, 2023, I attempted to live out my answer.
Invitation The message to friends read, with minor edits:
Please only attend the parts of the day that speak to you, and RSVP if you will join any part of the day! I am expecting some activities to be popular, some activities to involve only me, and for ~no-one to attend everything!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning my funeral</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/planning-my-funeral/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/planning-my-funeral/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scope-sensitive personal finance</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/scope-sensitive-personal-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/scope-sensitive-personal-finance/</guid>
      <description>Scope-sensitivity is one of my favorite ideas.
In this post, I will apply the concept to personal finance. The idea to do this is entirely due to my friend Arden. I&amp;rsquo;m just writing it down.
I&amp;rsquo;ll survey some options, then discuss what I take from them.
Options Transportation Food Consumer goods Finance Work [ANALYSIS]
best allocation for me
best allocation as function of cost of time
[TAKEAWAYS]
[NOTES]
wait, work seems like odd one out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal workout split</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/optimal-workout-split/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/optimal-workout-split/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ve gotten past novitiate weightlifting aches, enduring 4+ sessions weekly. How should you now split exercises across days?
My answer is: use the posterior-anterior split. One day for the muscles used in a deadlift (back, hamstrings, glutes) plus biceps, one day for more-or-less everything else (chest, front- and side-delts, triceps, quads, hip flexors).
Here&amp;rsquo;s why.
The goal We want to train muscle groups as intensively as possible, as frequently as possible, whilst not training the same muscle group within fewer than 48 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Things</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/favorite-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/favorite-things/</guid>
      <description>These are a few of my favorite things &amp;ndash; in every category!
Using this table, you can browse:
My product recommendations. My favorite holiday spots. My favorite passion fruit-based product finds. And much more besides. Please get in touch if you share a love for something here, or if you have a recommendation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favorite passion fruit products</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/passion-fruit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/passion-fruit/</guid>
      <description>This list is a work-in-progress. In descending order of preference:
Passion Fruit - agua de maracuya This &amp;ldquo;Passion Fruit&amp;rdquo; is a smoothie place in La Condesa (CDMX) that sells, among other treats, passion fruit juice by the bucket. My favorite passion fruit product of all time! I love that it isn&amp;rsquo;t too sweetened, and that the seeds have separated from the juice. The only problem is the large blocks of ice that they put in the buckets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some intuitions about fellowship programs</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/fellowship-programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/fellowship-programs/</guid>
      <description>Epistemic status: not sure how reliable my intuition is, but I do have more experience with these programs than most.
TL;DR Making sure &amp;gt;30 participants have regular opportunities to spontaneously gather, active programming, basic food and medical amenities, and common knowledge about visit dates hugely increases the benefit of residential fellowship programs.
For transparency, I should note a stronger, less confident belief of mine that I will not defend here. My instinct is that all of the above factors are not merely beneficial but necessary in order for these programs to be worth their cost (assuming that their goals are indeed as I describe below).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/my-heroes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/my-heroes/</guid>
      <description>I try to leave people off of my favourite things list.
Gareth Bale Alice Evans Cate Hall Derek Parfit </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/shaping-dayjectory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/shaping-dayjectory/</guid>
      <description>Suppose you agree with me that discussion of the &amp;ldquo;value of time&amp;rdquo; is ridden with conceptual confusion.
you seek a better way see conceptual confusion 1 notice that even if you can state how much better an hour of your time will be with friends vs alone, at cafe vs office, etc., you don&amp;rsquo;t know which hour this is occurring during toby has framework for this! Toby Ord presents a simple mathematical framework for understanding how reducing existential risk compares with other ways of influencing the longterm future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/time-money-dynamic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/time-money-dynamic/</guid>
      <description>A dynamic model of time-money trade-offs People who make somewhat explicit time-money trade-offs often use something like their average wage as a proxy for the price at which they are indifferent between spending money to save an hour and spending an hour to save money.
This is a reasonable start, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s mistaken for at least 3 reasons:
Most people cannot earn an extra one hours of wages by working one hour more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/time-value-differs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/time-value-differs/</guid>
      <description>When you purchase an hour of time, it is not immediately obvious how much value you get, because (1) different hours have different value, and (2) it is not always clear which hour you are purchasing.
Different hours have different value Ways in which an hour can be more valuable to you include:
Time of day: morning, evening. Social context: with friends, with family, with strangers, alone. Location: at home, at work, at an art studio, on a beach, in a hospital.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/trajectory-makes-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/digital-garden/trajectory-makes-sense/</guid>
      <description>The standard model of valuing time is ridden with conceptual confusion, and can easily lead to naive misvaluations of the true value of time.
Is there a better alternative?
One possibility is to borrow from Toby Ord&amp;rsquo;s framework for thinking about shaping the value of humanity&amp;rsquo;s longterm trajectory. Ord presents a framework</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
