<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joel Becker</title>
    <link>https://joel-becker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Joel Becker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joel-becker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Diet is endogenous to exercise</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/personal/exercise-vs-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/personal/exercise-vs-diet/</guid>
      <description>There is a near-consensus that diet is more important than exercise, at least for aesthetics.
I think this idea suffers from a similar problem as that suffered by &amp;lsquo;calories in calories out&amp;rsquo;: although it might be true in some idealized sense, &amp;ldquo;calories out are endogenous to what is eaten&amp;rdquo;.
Here, diet-in-reality is largely determined by &amp;rsquo;the kind of person you believe yourself to be.&amp;rsquo; Exercising more makes it easier to see yourself as the kind of person who takes diet seriously, and therefore improves diet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masked Mixer</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/personal/masked-mixer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/personal/masked-mixer/</guid>
      <description>My friend Arden and I thought it would be fun to host some kind of event themed around sensory deprivation (or heightening). We brainstormed some possibilities:
In the end we put on a &amp;ldquo;masked mixer,&amp;rdquo; consisting of a fully blindfolded dinner, games of jenga, and hide-and-seek.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural talents</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/personal/natural-talents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/personal/natural-talents/</guid>
      <description>Roasting marshmallows. Calf strength (when standing). Seriously, I can do ~900 pounds through a full range of motion for 10-12 reps. Confidence (but not competence) for public speaking. Confidence for hosting events that might fail. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that most of these &amp;rsquo;natural&amp;rsquo; (by which I mean occurring without practice) talents are (1) almost entirely useless and/or (2) challenging to teach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O-1</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/personal/cost-of-o1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/personal/cost-of-o1/</guid>
      <description>Not legal advice.
I learned a lot from the authors of these great guides on getting an O-1 visa (1, 2).
When I shared this on twitter, I was surprised how many questions I got about the process. There are</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect Day</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/personal/perfect-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/personal/perfect-day/</guid>
      <description>The 4th of the famous 36 questions for falling in love is: &amp;ldquo;What would constitute a &amp;lsquo;perfect&amp;rsquo; day for you?&amp;rdquo; On September 10th, 2023, I attempted to live out my answer.
Invitation The message to friends read, with minor edits:
Please only attend the parts of the day that speak to you, and RSVP if you will join any part of the day! I am expecting some activities to be popular, some activities to involve only me, and for ~no-one to attend everything!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two analogies for being less smart than someone</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/personal/analogies-for-smarts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/personal/analogies-for-smarts/</guid>
      <description>starting with that quote about von neumann being good with kids, maybe treating scientists the same way
Seeing through clouds In 200X, Masha Gessen wrote a series of articles for Slate about X. [CAME TO THE ECONOMIST DAVID]
I&amp;rsquo;ve had a number of similar interactions with David. He seems to have this (from my perspective) superhuman ability to cut through the crap, to highlight the pivotal issue in some decision directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal workout split</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/personal/optimal-workout-split/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/personal/optimal-workout-split/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ve transcended beyond the novitiate aches of weightlifting, mastering the discipline to endure 4+ sessions weekly. Now, how should you best split exercises across days?
My answer is: use the posterior-anterior split. One day for the muscles used in a deadlift (back, hamstrings, glutes) plus biceps, one day for more-or-less everything else (chest, front- and side-delts, triceps, quads, hip flexors).
Here&amp;rsquo;s why.
The goal We want to train muscle groups as intensively as possible, as frequently as possible, whilst not training the same muscle group within fewer than 48 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Things</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/personal/favorite-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/personal/favorite-things/</guid>
      <description>These are a few of my favorite things &amp;ndash; in every category!
Using this table, you can browse:
My product recommendations. My favorite holiday spots. My favorite passion fruit-based product finds. And much more besides. Please get in touch if you share a love for something here, or if you have a recommendation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitness advice for someone exactly like me</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/personal/fitness-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/personal/fitness-advice/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m occasionally asked for fitness advice. (Credentials at the end.) Here it is, with one small caveat: for best results, you should be exactly like me. I am not promising methods that fit most people&amp;rsquo;s goals! My advice might be helpful to the extent that you:
Care about appearances at least as much as other fitness goals (health, flexibility, strength, etc.). Are happy to do non-weightlifting sports no more than twice per week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favorite passion fruit products</title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/personal/passion-fruit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/personal/passion-fruit/</guid>
      <description>This list is a work-in-progress. In descending order of preference:
Passion Fruit - agua de maracuya This &amp;ldquo;Passion Fruit&amp;rdquo; is a smoothie place in La Condesa (CDMX) that sells, among other treats, passion fruit juice by the bucket. My favorite passion fruit product of all time! I love that it isn&amp;rsquo;t too sweetened, and that the seeds have separated from the juice. The only problem is the large blocks of ice that they put in the buckets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joel-becker.com/personal/cafes-to-exist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joel-becker.com/personal/cafes-to-exist/</guid>
      <description>One day, once I have long-term security in where I live, I want to open a series of cafes.
Sauna and ice baths cafe. Dog cafe. Plant shop cafe. Austrian delicatessen-cafe. Napolitan cafe. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
